

Omar Reda
Front-End Developer

# CONTACT



+201094407154



omarmreda95@gmail.com



Cairo, Egypt



<u>linkedin.com/in/omarmreda</u>



github.com/omarmreda



gitlab.com/omarmreda95

## **SKILLS**

- HTML
- SASS

CSS

- Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- Angular
- React.js
- Git
- Redux
- Next.JS

## **LANGUAGES**

**English** Fluent

Arabic Native

French Beginner

#### **SUMMARY**

As a frontend developer I am Looking forward to contribute my skills in web development to create user friendly web experience with collaborative mindset and dedication to produce high quality work with solid understanding of frontend foundations and responsive design principles.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Frontend Developer (IVAS - Cairo) Full-time

April, 2023 – Current

- Building Different projects for Skydive pharaohs, Society of Authors and other clients.
- Developed different frontend features for different websites.
- Using: React, Next.Js, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Material UI, Angular

#### Frontend Developer (Freelance)

December, 2022 - April, 2023

- Developing different frontend features and different UI Components for Ecommerce Website.
- Using :- JavaScript , HTML5 , Angular , React.js

# Architect Site Engineer (Orbita for Contracting) April, 2020 – December, 2022

 Working in construction field as an architect site engineer , Implementing mega projects

### PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

**Udacity Cross-Skilling Track (React.Js)** 

April, 2022

Studied: JSX, Hooks, Functional Components, Routes.

**Udacity Professional Front-End Development (Nano-Degree)** 

March , 2022

Studied: JavaScript, ES6, Web API, Node.js, Agile.

**Udacity Foundational Web Development (Nano-Degree)** 

February, 2022

Studied: HTML, CSS, Basics of WordPress.

### **PROJECTS**

#### Sky-dive pharaohs (Ongoing)

July , 2023

- Developing Frontend interface for skydive agency using Angular, Tailwind
- The Project is currently in development phase
- Live: https://skydive.vercel.app/
- Code: https://gitlab.com/Development.ivas/skydive\_react

## **Personal Portfolio**

December, 2022

- Developing personal portfolio using React , Css3
- Live : <a href="https://portfolioomarreda.vercel.app/">https://portfolioomarreda.vercel.app/</a>

#### **EDUCATION**

# The British University in Egypt

2013 -2018

Bachelor of Engineering – Faculty of Architecture Engineering

Validated from Loughborough University - UK

#### VOLUNTEERING

## **AIESEC Cairo (Incoming Global Entrepreneur Team leader)**

2017 – 2018

Helping 100+people from different counties to get internships and volunteering projects